Yokoya
Yes, coming!
Right, uh...
Could I ask who's...
Forgive me for the imposition,
but would you be willing
to employ me as your servant?
Out of the blue one day,
a maid showed up to work.
Episode 1: My Fateful Encounter with You.
I'm sorry. My parents aren't around
currently, so the place is a mess.
It's fine.
Oh, would you like something to drink?
Please don't trouble yourself.
I let her in without thinking, but...
Gyokuro Tea
Did she really come here to work?
She's not trying to scam me
or sell something shady, right?
Maybe I'll just ask some token questions
and have her go home.
Gyokuro Tea
Um...
Since you're a servant, you must have
previously worked somewhere, right?
What kind of work did you mainly do?
Well, let's see.
I mainly performed assassinations and such,
though only to kill disloyal men
who wronged my master.
My master was the one
who referred me to this place.
Um, that was a joke, right?
A joke?
She needs to leave!
I just have to get her out of here
without upsetting her!
Um... What did you mean when you said
your master referred you?
Do they have some kind of
connection with our family?
You are the grandson of a woman
who used to freeload off of
my master's legitimate child's
wife's cousin's second son.
That's practically a stranger!
Oh! Oh, no! I cut her off
and played the straight man!
Eek, she kinda looks mad!
I have to change the subject!
S-So, assassination, huh?
I understand there are all kinds of methods.
Which do you specialize in?
What do you think?
Prideful much?
I don't often throw them in practice,
but I thought doing it this way
would make it easier to demonstrate my skills.
U-Um... I don't have anyone
I need a-assassinated.
And I'm not familiar with this
master of yours who referred you.
I don't really understand
why you're here, but...
I'm afraid... I can't...
hire you.
I see.
My apologies for troubling you.
Now then, if you will excuse me.
Did I dream all that?
Hm?
That's practically a stranger!
What was I getting so excited for?
Where should I go now....
Hey!
Ms. Servant! You forgot this!
Watch where you're going!
Ms... Servant?
A-Are... you all right?
Th-Thank you.
M-My apologies.
I've never saved someone's
life like this before, and...
M-My heart won't stop pounding.
Here... You left this behind.
Thank you.
Ms. Servant!
I've actually been looking for someone
to help with the cleaning.
Can I ask for your assistance?
Yokoya
The knife,
said to be the very first tool
ever employed by mankind.
Simple enough for anyone to use,
and yet, in the hands of a practiced wielder,
it can reliably end a target's life.
W-Wait, wait, stop!
I-I know I said something
along the lines of needing help,
but what I want you to do is clean!
You know, cleaning!
Clean... Cleaning...
Yes. I know all about "cleaning."
Not in the assassination sense!
What other kind of "cleaning" would it be?
Oh, come on. Look at this mess of a room!
And yes, I'm the one who made said mess, but!
I see.
One of these must be a body bag—
Let's move away from that for one second!
I mean, like, you know... Taking out
the trash, vacuuming, doing laundry...
What I need is a housekeeper!
A housekeeper...
She did save my life, after all,
and she doesn't seem like a bad person.
If I could do this housework,
you would hire me?
Yokoya
What just happened?
I only just gave her the equipment!
How can she be so clumsy?!
M-M-My apologies.
I-I will clean this up right away—
Ms. Servant...
I'm sorry to have worried you.
I cannot be embarrassing myself any—
Oh, man.
Ms. Servant, are you...
somewhat—no, extremely...
clumsy?
I am truly sorry.
After a string of blunders like these,
I'm sure you no longer wish to hire me.
Well, I was the one who asked you to do
something you weren't used to, and...
It's never too late to start learning, right?
I'll help, too.
No, let's clean up together.
Will you help me?
Whoa!
The living room looks so tidy!
We're off to a great start!
I just couldn't motivate myself
to do it on my own.
You really helped me out. Thanks!
Oh, man! I didn't realize how late it was!
I had so much going on
that I forgot to eat lunch.
Oh!
By any chance, would you happen
to be able to cook...
Ah... Yeah, sorry.
No worries! I have the ultimate menu
already in mind for tonight!
So feel free to use the bath first!
You really helped me out. Thanks!
My name is Hitoyoshi Yokoya!
I'm your average sophomore in high school.
I'm fully enjoying a summer vacation
without my parents around,
and right now I'm feeling
more nervous than ever!
After all, a maid suddenly showed up
claiming to be an assassin...
No, not because of that!
Wh-What should I do?!
Knowing that lady, she's probably going to
carelessly come out wearing only a towel—
Um...
Y-Yes?!
Thank you for allowing me to bathe first.
My lost youth!
Um, you don't have to force yourself, okay?
That's quite all right. Knifework is the
one thing I'm better at than anyone else.
I have finished shredding the cabbage!
Th-Thank you.
All that's left is to prepare the instant
miso soup and place the tonkatsu side dish!
Tonkatsu...
Huh? Do you not know what tonkatsu is?
I may have eaten something
resembling it in the past.
However, I have little interest in food,
and I tend not to remember much about it.
I've always thought of food as something
ingested solely to sustain oneself,
and so I've never cared
about its taste or form.
Are you serious?! What a waste!
But... Your world is about to change
once you try this tonkatsu!
Ta-da!
Established 60 years ago,
Katsuda Side Dish Store
the Katsuda Side Dish Store is the pride
of our town's shopping district!
Pumpkin Croquette
130 yen
Minced Meat Croquette
Croquette
110 yen
Early in the morning, Mr. and
Mrs. Katsuda carefully prepare
side dishes that are
not only cheap but delicious!
Katsuda Side Dish Store
It's rumored that even famous celebrities
secretly turn up for a taste!
And now, without further ado...
Please enjoy Katsuda's tonkatsu!
You're kidding me!
That was the dullest reaction yet!
Um... Please go ahead and eat.
No worries!
If we do this...
and do that... See!
Dinner for two is served!
For me and you, Ms. Serv—
Come to think of it...
What is your name, Ms. Servant?
A name... I don't have a name.
Until now, I've had my employer
call me whatever they wish to call me.
So you, too, may call me
whatever you wish, Master Yokoya.
Oh, really? Hm...
Well, if that's okay, I guess I'll stick
with Ms. Servant for now?
Apparently I suck at coming up with names.
That's strange.
I never cared about what name
I was called until now...
Now, then!
Let's eat!
Let us eat.
Yep! Delish! I might just be a genius!
Wh-What do you think?
As usual,
I can't distinguish whether
it tastes good or bad.
However...
I feel... warmth.
How is it? Good?
Yes. It is most delicious.
I'm glad to hear that!
I feel warmth...
From the bath, the meal...
and this person, as well.
Oh! Is it okay if your room is the end room
on the second floor, Ms. Servant?
Oh...
I put on fresh bed sheets and pillow covers,
but if anything's wrong, just tell me, okay?
You prepared a room for me...?
Yep!
A name...
I don't have a name.
You pass.
You have skin that's white as snow,
and a heart that's just as cold.
Starting today, your name is...
I don't have a name.
I see. So that's why.
I don't want him to call me
something that means "cold."
Hm... Oh? You're eating
that tonkatsu on its own.
Was I not supposed to?
You need tonkatsu sauce for tonkatsu.
This one's a Katsuda Side Dish Store original!
Tonkatsu sauce...
Katsuda's Sauce
Oh!
Was it delicious?
Ye...sh...
Katsuda's Sauce
Tonkatsu... sauce...
It's been a while since I had that dream.
I think I've got some cup ramen left.
What?! There's someone in the kitchen?!
I mainly performed assassinations...
No way...
I-It can't be, right?
Oh! Um!
I-I was just... My apologies!
No, it's fine.
That's several loads off my mind.
Were you hungry, Ms. Servant?
I got hungry, too, so...
Well, I...
When I thought of how any day—
tomorrow included—could be my last,
I was thinking I wouldn't want to die without
tasting this sauce one last time, so...
Then I have a great idea!
Pseudo sauce fondue!
The ingredients aren't anything
to write home about, but...
Eat up, eat up!
Tonkatsu... sauce...
Do you just like the taste of the sauce itself?
Um...
Did you have some kind of
scary dream, Master Yokoya?
Huh? Why do you ask?
When I left my bed to go lick the s-sauce,
I heard groaning coming from your room.
I considered the very real possibility
of an assassination attempt
and excused myself into your room.
What possibility, exactly?!
So... did you see me?
Th-That's so embarrassing! Did I say anything?
Yes. You said "Mom" numerous times.
I also...
had a dream.
The tonkatsu sauce started to talk to me.
Katsuda's Sauce
Talk?
It said, "I'm this big, so no matter how
much you lick me, I won't run out."
"You can have as much as you like."
But when I went in for a lick, I woke up.
Oh, man... It's the super sad kind.
Still...
It was a first for me.
Up until now, my only dreams have
been about killing or being killed.
And I never felt anything in particular
from my dreams, or from waking up.
It was the first time I ever felt
like I wanted to keep dreaming.
That's why...
I felt a little sorry that you had
to have a nightmare on a day like this.
And above that, that I didn't know
of any ways to make you feel better.
That is what made me feel
so sad and unfulfilled.
Sorry to make you worry.
I have that dream every once in a while.
Mom... Where are you going?
Mom...
I always had nightmares as a child,
and whenever I would wake up crying,
I could never get back to sleep without
resting my head on my mom's lap.
Resting on a lap...
Then...
Please rest on my lap.
What?
No! No, no, no, no!
That was back when I was a kid!
Right now, I'm an ordinary boy who
understands public order and morals!
And besides, an adolescent boy
shouldn't be... Huh?
As I thought, I'm not...
You were born only to kill.
I'm... I'm not...
Oh... I feel so cold...
So soft!
It's so warm!
Yes... For me, too.
Um... Master Yokoya?
Uh, um... You can just
call me Hitoyoshi, so...
U-Understood.
Then I think... I'll be...
Do you think you can sleep
now, Master Hitoyoshi?
Yokoya
Yeah... Thank you.
This is a story about how a
lonely maid found a family.